Aaron Gilmore

Digital designer and front-end developer

About

My name is Aaron Gilmore and I'm a digital designer working primarily on the web.

I've been working professionally for over 4 years in various roles; interface design for both the web and native mobile, front-end web development, prototyping, and project management.

Education

Interactive Multimedia Design BSc, University of Ulster Second-class honours, upper division (2:1) September 2011—May 2015

Contact

Email: hello@aarongilmore.com Website: aarongilmore.com Mobile: +44 (0)7706 554614 Twitter: @aarondgilmore

Professional Experience

Sports Fusion; remote, 2015—2017

- Front-end web development on core systems for clients including: Arsenal, Wimbledon, Manchester City, Formula E, and more
- · Project and team management
- Early development of a design system for future projects

Brewbot; Belfast, 2012-2014

- Interface design for the web and native mobile; our marketing website, store, and iOS app
- Front-end web development
- · Various print design projects for marketing purposes
- · Harware design and testing
- Planned, launched, and managed a Kickstarter campiagn that raised over £100k
- Manufactured and shipped Kickstarter rewards worldwide
- Part of the 2014 Techstars accelerator program in Austin, Texas

Ecliptic Labs; Belfast, 2012—2013 (internship)

- iOS and web design
- · Web development
- Asset production for the iOS development team
- · Software testing

Freelance designer; 2009—2010, 2017—present

- Various content management systems for clients
- Front-end development of a web app and marketing website for Performa Sports, a sports analysis company

Skills

- · Project planning and development
- Interface design for both the web and native mobile (Sketch, Adobe CC)
- Front-end web development (HTML, SCSS/LESS, JavaScript, jQuery, Gulp, NPM)
- Version control using Git (GitHub, BitBucket)
- Experience with project management software (Slack, InVision, Trello, Jira)
- · Prototyping interactions (Framer.js, Origami)
- Some experience with Objective-C, PHP, Ruby, and Ember
- CMS experience (Wordpress, Perch, Squarespace)

Personal

- Avid traveller, having travelled through Europe and the US. Very keen to visit Asia in the near future
- I like to attend conferences as much as possible; most recently XOXO in Portland OR. and Hybrid in Dublin, Ireland.
- · Active participant in community meetups and events